PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Over five years of experience in Software Quality Assurance testing in both SDLC and Agile methodology environments. Expertise in testing Web, client/server and database oriented applications. Demonstrates skills in various forms of testing as well as defect tracking and reporting. Involved with manual and automated testing using Test Director, Quality Center, and Quick Test Professional. A professional with a solid understanding of the System Development Life Cycle (SDLC). Maintains a high level of work commitment; utilizes excellent interpersonal and communication skills with entire project team, and possesses a high level of analytical skills.

TESTING EXPERTISE

Defect Reporting UAT Testing Create Test Cases Write Test Report **End-to-end Testing** Install/Uninstall Testing **Black Box Testing** System Testing **Integration Testing** Regression Testing **Recovery Testing** Stress Testing Performance Testing Load Testing **Functional Testing** Alpha Testing Create Test Scripts Acceptance Testing Ad Hoc Testing Sanity Testing

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Testing Tools Mercury Quick Test Professional, Mercury Winrunner, LoadRunner

Bug Reports Mercury Test Director/Quality Center, Bugzilla, Atlassian Jira TestTrack Seapine

Databases Oracle, MS SQL Server, My SQL,

Languages SQL, XML

Platforms Microsoft Vista/XP/2000,2008, MS Windows 2010,

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Position: Software Quality Assurance Analyst

Company: PAREXEL International,

Location: Irvine, CA

Duration: June 2010- Oct 2012

Description: The project incorporates two applications that work with each other for use by Clinical Research Associates (CRA) for creation and maintenance of clinical trial studies. The application maintains all events, and

study data from the beginning to completion of a clinical trial study.

Responsibilities:

- Working in an Agile methodology environment for two phases of the project focusing on two softwares: Datalabs Designer and Datalabs. Both are utilized by Clinical Research Associates for clinical trial studies.
- Working on specific sections of the project in an environment with a Scrum team approach; working directly and extensively with Project Managers, Business Analysts, Database Analysts, Developers and SQA to meet software requirements at the end of each three-week sprint.

- Responsible for creating User Scenarios, Test Ideas, Test Outlines, Test Cases and Scripts to manually
 execute during software testing of both Datalabs Designer and Datalabs.
- Conducting GUI, Ad Hoc, Functional, Black Box, Regression, Positive, and Negative Testing to ensure the application is working as per requirements.
- Played a role in designing functional parts of a specific aspect of the Datalabs software for ease of use by clients.
- Utilized TestTrack Seapine to log all defects and issues for both applications.
- Assisted in training colleagues on parts of the application to ensure thorough testing is conducted.

Position: Quality Assurance Analyst Company: Arts & Technologies Inc,

Location: Torrance, CA

Duration: February 2008- June 2010

Description: The project is a web-based application for administration to maintain new hires and enrollments, changes, terminations, and monthly invoice review for company sub contractors. Also, a web interface for the contractors to manage and keep track of their contracts.

Responsibilities:

- Created test plan and test specifications as per requirements in project documents.
- Incorporated and used Test Director to log all defects including documentation issues.
- Automated the test cases for GUI testing using Quick Test Professional.
- Tested a range of check points (GUI, Bitmap, Database, Text) to test whether numerous GUI and field objects meet the requirement specifications.
- Performed Black Box and Regression testing; smoke, manual and automated testing was done across the entire application and test data was created for test cases.
- Used SQL queries to ensure correct data and information was being generated across entire application.
- Tested cross browser functionality including browsers Internet Explorer, Netscape, Safari and Firefox.
- Before release of a new version of application, created appropriate and useful testing release notes.
- Fully discussed project concerns and updates in project review and defect review board meetings to verify and review defects reported against the application in its current version.

Position: Quality Assurance Analyst

Company: Hythiam Inc. Location: Santa Monica, CA

Duration: December 2007- February 2008

Description: The project "ITMS" Integrated Treatment Management System is a web-based application to be used by a patient's Provider, the Care Coach and the patients themselves. ITMS is used to maintain a very large patient database and to track patient progress; data includes patient's personal information, health conditions, addictions, etc. **Responsibilities:**

- Based on Business Requirements analysis and Use Case, created the Test Plan, Test Scenarios, Test Cases, and Test Scripts and manually executed the Scripts successfully.
- Integrated and implemented Bug Tracker software into the company for use by QA, BSAs, and Developers.
- Performed UAT testing across numerous software components before new version release to test for any functional problems/defects for customer usability purposes.
- Performed System, Functional, Integration, Positive, Negative, and Regression testing across entire software application.
- Performed extensive Ad Hoc testing to search for small or fatal errors in various components of software.
- Executed search queries to search for patient records for the purpose of back-end testing.
- Thoroughly discussed the defect report with developers and Project Manager for defect resolutions.

Fullerton, California (714) 767-6558 sobia.razak@yahoo.com

- Worked directly and extensively with Lead, and Project Manager to organize test plans for different stages of software development.
- Worked efficiently with each QA team member to implement cross training of various applications of software.

Position: Software QA Analyst Company: Thomson Elite **Location:** Los Angeles, CA

Duration: September 2007 – December 2007

Description: Thomson Elite creates billing products for use by the legal industry. Analyzed and tested a web-based product called 3E. 3E is an all-encompassing software that includes various applications for use by legal firms. Applications include Calendar Management, Conflicts, Reports, Billing, Collections, Profitability, etc.

Responsibilites:

- Based on the Use Case and Functional Design Specifications (FDS) analysis, created test cases, test scenarios, and test scripts for manual testing process.
- Performed Sanity Testing in Calendar Management application and tested functionality for billing clients, scheduling and creating events and tasks.
- Raised Change Requests for 3E V2.3 Calendar Management application on StarTeam V1.0.
- Executed Regression Testing for possible errors after all enhancements put in place.
- Used SQL queries to run reports; search for past present and future events and tasks related to particular clients.
- Created UAT Test Cases, Test Scripts based on functional requirements.
- Performed UAT Testing due to many enhancements in newest software version to ensure application is functioning effectively and ensure ease of use for end user.
- Performed Ad Hoc, Positive, and Negative Testing to test for possible breaks in software code.
- Worked efficiently with QA teams and individuals to implement cross training of various applications of software.
- Extensive communication with application Developers and Business Analysts to track progress project.

EDUCATION

Bachelors Degree in Business Administration California State University of Fullerton

^{*}References available upon request.